股票，债券今天全都上涨了…
Stocks and bonds are moving higher....
我们为什么看商业台？
Why are we watching the Business Channel?
因为我前几天看到有支股票 是我的名字的缩写MEG
Because the other day I saw there was a stock with my initials,MEG,on it.
有时我得苦等两，三个小时 才又会再看到
Sometimes it takes two or three hours before it comes up again.
但是看到的时候蛮兴奋的
But when it does,it's exciting.
亲爱的，我看你是真的需要工作
Okay,honey,you really need a job.
莫妮卡，说到这个，爸说 他认识一个人你可以去应征
Dad says he knows someone you can call for an interview.
那是今天的第三个预兆了 看！
Right there! That's the third sign today. Right there.
我在替在座的每一位 说一声“什么？”
On behalf of everyone,I'd just like to say,"Huh?"
因为你刚刚说了“爸” 今天我不管到什么地方去…
No,you just said "dad." And everywhere I go today...
…我都一直得到叫我去看我爸的预兆
... I keep getting signs telling me to go see my father.
像我来这里的时候 我经过一个自助餐厅（buffet）
Like when I was walking over here and I passed a buffet.
跟我爸爸的姓(布菲)发音相近
Which is my father's last name.
我爸爸的名字是弗兰克…
And they were serving franks...
…而他们也有弗兰克福香肠
...which is his first name minus the "s" at the end.
还有一家烤架上有鸡（有“胆小”的意思）在转的烤鸡店
And there was a rotisserie with a spinning chicken.
他的印第安名？
His lndian name?
不是，因为我上次去见他时“胆小”地逃跑了…
No. Because I chickened out the last time...
…这么巧合吗？ 我不认为哦
...when I tried to meet him. So coincidences? I don't think so.
好奇怪 怪透了
-Very freaky. -Eerie.
最后一个汉堡谁要？
Who wants the last hamburger?
好了，够了，我非去不可了
That's it. Now I have to go see him.
为什么？
Why?
汉堡？麦当劳？
Hamburger? McDonald's?
老麦当劳有个农场（儿歌“咿呀咿呀哦”的歌词） 我爸是药剂师（与“农场”谐音）
Old McDonald had a farm. My dad is a pharmacist.
并且“咿呀咿呀哦”就是你爸爸抛弃你妈妈时 她说的话
And E-l-E-l-O is what your mom said when your dad left her.
-是的 -真的？-不是
-Yes.-Really?-No.
六人行 第2季 第21集 两个小流氓
The One With the Bullies
老兄，我累歪了
Man,I am so beat.
我们最好别去打什么球了 留在这里混吧
You wanna forget racquetball and hang out?
对，好吧
Yeah,all right.
那是我们的位置 抱歉，我们不知道
-Hey,you're in our seats. -Sorry,we didn't know.
我们本来坐那里的
We were sitting there.
这还有另外一种说法
Okay. There is one more way to say it.
谁知道？
Who knows it?
你这是在说笑话吗？ 不，我在说多姿多采的话
-Was that supposed to be funny? -Actually,I was going for colorful.
这家伙怎么了？ 你怎么了？
-What's with this guy? -What's with you?
没什么，他没怎么
Nothing. Nothing's with him.
请慢用咖啡
Enjoy your coffee.
发生了什么事了？
What just happened?
我刚拿了你的帽子 你看，我也能妙趣横生
I just took your hat. See,I can be funny too.
我的笑话就是拿了你的帽子
My joke is that I took your hat.
那真有趣啊
That is funny.
还给我，好吗？
Can I have it back?
-不行？ -不行
-No？ -No
你知道吗？我觉得你很风趣
You know what? I think you're very funny.
那个笑话真该受到奖赏
Kudos on that hat joke.
别这样，两位 把帽子还给他嘛
But come on,guys,just give him back the hat.
为什么？
Why should we?
因为那是顶特别的帽子
Because it's a special hat.
有一天他的心情很不好
He bought it because he was feeling down one day.
所以他就买了那顶帽子…
So he got the hat...
…来帮自己打气
...to cheer himself up,you know?
钱德… 别说了，别再说了
-Chandler -Stop talking. Stop talking now.
让我先搞清楚 你抢了我的帽子？
Let me get this straight. You're stealing my hat?
你有意见吗？
You got a problem?
不，我只是想确定我们的观点一致
I just want to make sure we're on the same page.
跟你说瑞秋,上一次我和菲比去找她父亲.
I'm telling you Rach, I've gone dad-hunting with Phoebe before.
这对她来说她恐怖了,她有点脆弱.
This is a very scary thing for her.She gets real vulnerable and...
这就是为什么我们要去,互相支持或者垮掉
...that's why we' re there,to be supportive and crap.
好,你只是告诉我什么时间去就行了
Okay. You just let me know when to do which.
面试结果怎么样？
How'd the interview go?
逊毙了
It bit.
那是一家50年代主题的餐厅
It was a 50s theme restaurant.
我得穿戏服做菜在柜台上跳舞
I'd have to cook in a costume and dance on the counter.
我以前是艺术咖啡（著名法国餐馆）的主厨耶
I was a sous chef at Cafe des Artistes.
我是说，我怎能接受一个 我得做炸绿色卷曲东西的工作呢
How can I take a job where I have to make Laverne-and-Curly Fries?
那就别做啊 我怎么能不做呢？
-Don't do it. -How can I not do it?
我银行里面只剩下127块了
I have $127 in the bank!
莫妮卡，放轻松，去拿瓶啤酒
Monica,relax. Go get a beer.
我不想喝啤酒
I don't want a beer.
谁说是给你的？
Who said it was for you?
你们两个怎么了？
What's the matter?
咖啡厅里 有两个卑鄙的家伙抢了我的帽子
Some mean guys at the coffeehouse took my hat.
不会吧 你开玩笑？
-No! -You're kidding?
简直荒唐透了 这些人是流氓
It was ridiculous. These guys were bullies.
是真正的流氓
Actual bullies.
你看，我们是大人了 我们不该会再碰上这种事了
We're grownups. This kind of stuff isn't supposed to happen anymore.
不，等一下，我没有人抱
Oh,no,wait a minute. I have no one.
我们应该过去把帽子给拿回来
Let's go down there and get your hat back.
算了吧，说不定 已经被拆成零件给卖掉了
Forget it. It's probably stripped and sold for parts by now.
我涨了 什么？
-I went up! -What?
我的股票MEG，涨了两点
My stock,MEG,it went up two points.
若我昨天把我的127元 投资在我自己身上…
Do you realize that if I'd invested my $127 in myself yesterday...
…那我就会比我今天有钱了
...that l'd,like,have a lot more than that today.
知道吗？我要放手一搏
You know what? I'm going to do it.
搏什么？ 拿钱投资我
-Do what? -Put all my money in me.
莫妮卡，你在说什么？ 你对股市一窍不通
You don't know a thing about the stock market.
要通什么？ 买，卖，高，低，熊市，牛市
What's to know? Buy,sell. High,low. Bears,bulls.
喂，曼哈顿
Yes,Manhattan.
麻烦帮我查个电话号码，股票…
Telephone number for the stock...
…商店
...selling store.
你看 我说应该带枕头来是对的吧
See? I told you these pillows would be a good idea.
天啊
Oh,God.
就这样了
Here we go.
我就要说出我这辈子的 第一声“嗨，生父”了
For the first time in my life,I'm gonna say,"Hi,Birth Father!"
我们爱你，我们支持你 一切顺利
-We love you. We're here for you. -Good luck.
谢谢
Thanks.
瑞秋，要不要三明治？
Hey,Rach,you want some sandwich?
里面有什么？
What is in that?
橄榄面包，火腿片，没有蛋黄酱
Olive loaf and ham spread. No mayo.
不…再加蛋黄酱就恶心了
No,because mayo,that would make it gross.
跑，菲比，跑… 不要，狗狗，拜托
-Run,Phoebe,run! -No,no,doggy,please!
我爱所有的动物 所以请不要这样，退后
I do so want to love all animals. Please,no. Back off!
有没有骨头？ 开什么玩笑？
-You got a bone? -Are you kidding?
看…那有狗食，去吃吧
Look,kibbles! Bits!
放开我的腿 你这只烂东西
Get the hell off my leg,you yippity piece of crap!
好了，我们碰上难题了
Okay. All right. We have a problem.
你为什么不把它的弹簧垫拿走？
Why don't you take his trampoline?
我知道怎么办了
Okay,here,I know what we can do.
狗狗，去捡三明治
Okay,doggy,get the sandwich!
去捡三明治啊，好狗狗 快点
Go get the sandwich! Good doggy. Get the sandwich!
乔伊，它宁可舔自己 也不碰你的三明治
The dog will lick himself but he will not touch your sandwich.
那代表什么？
What does that tell you?
它不吃的话，我自己吃 你疯了你？
-lf he's not going to eat it,I will. -Are you crazy?
它是小狗而已
He's just a little dog.
嘿 干嘛？
-Hey. -What?
一定要当21世纪的房地产经纪人…
Do you have to be a Century 21 real-estate agent...
…才能穿着那么酷的外套吗？
...to get to wear those cool jackets?
你会跟女生这样搭讪吗？
Do you say this stuff to girls?
那不是你帽子的旧主人吗？
Isn't that the guy who used to wear your hat?
看他们坐在哪里了
And look where they're sitting.
你在说笑吧？你们才刚进门
You're joking,right? You guys just walked through the door.
或许我们说得不够清楚
Maybe we didn't make it clear enough.
这个沙发是我们的
This couch belongs to us.
这样吧，你们叫一声沙发…
I'll tell you what,you call the couch...
…然后我们也对着它叫一声…
...and then we'll call the couch...
…看它会到谁那里去
...and we'll see who it comes to.
知道我最不喜欢你哪一点吗？你总是不停地说话
Know what I don't like about you?.You always got something to say.
那个…
Well, that
我一直不懂 你们为什么还赖在这个地方？
You know,I keep wondering why you two are still sitting here.
好了，够了
All right,that's it.
我受够了，好吗？
I have had enough of this.
甘瑟
Gunther.
这两个家伙 想抢我们的座位
These guys are trying to take our seat.
两位，他们先来的
Fellas,these guys were here first.
抱歉，我们不知道
Oh,sorry,didn't realize.
好了
There you go.
谢谢，甘瑟
Thank you,Gunther.
是你们逼我们这么做的
We didn't want to have to go and do that.
他打小报告？
He told on us?
你打小报告？
You told on us?
兄弟，你们逼得我别无选择
Well,pal,you didn't give me much of a choice.
-别耍他 -我知道
-Don't play with his thing. -I know.
很好
All right.
我们到外面解决
Let's take this outside.
“我们到外面解决”？
"Let's take this outside?"
谁会这么说？
Who talks like that?
即将要痛扁你们的人会这么说
The guy who's about to kick your ass talks like that.
谁叫你多嘴呢
You had to ask.
好吧…
Okay,okay,look. See...
…我们不想用武力来解决
...the thing is,we're not gonna fight you guys.
那么这样好了
Here's the deal.
你们保证从今以后 不踏入这家咖啡厅
You won't have to,so long as you never ever show your faces here again.
我认为你太早把甘瑟抬出来了
I think you played the Gunther card too soon.
菲比，我想你可以上去了
Hey,Pheebs,I think you're good to go.
我不知道
Yeah,I don't know.
又怎么了？
What's the matter?
我是觉得这是个很不好的预兆
I just think that this was a really bad sign.
我是说像门槛上的野兽啦
Like the beast at the threshold.
我已经没有别的亲人了 除了我外婆之外
It's just I have no family left,except for my grandmother.
可是面对现实吧 她又不会永远都活着
But let's face it,she's not gonna be around forever.
不管怎么说
Despite what she says.
我有个同在子宫里面开始就几乎没有说过话的姐姐
And I have a sister who I've barely spoken to since we shared a womb.
这是我真正的父亲…
I don't know. This is my real father...
…我只是要一切正常
...and I want things to be,like,just right.
我完全了解
I completely understand.
对，随你要怎么样
Whatever you need.
你要回家吗？
Hey,you want to go home?
谢了，对不起
Okay,thanks. Sorry,again.
那是什么？
What was that?
我猜现在门前没有阻碍了
I'm guessing the threshold's clear now.
我要买五股SGJ 我现在就要
I want to buy five shares of SGJ. Now.
快点，时间就是金钱
Come on,time is money,my friend!
谢谢
Thank you!
“时间就是金钱”？
"Time is money,my friend?"
你错过了“用钱去赚钱”…
You missed "Takes money to make money"...
…还有，“别逼我 过去踢你的华尔街屁股”
...and "Don't make me come down there and kick your Wall Street butt."
我早餐前就赚了十七块耶 那你做了什么？
I made $ 17 before breakfast. What have you done?
我早餐在这个地方吃的 所以理论上我省了三块五
I had breakfast here,so technically I saved $3.50.
你怎么赚十七块的？
How did you make $17?
我在经济上很有挑战性的朋友们：
Well,my financially challenged friends...
…我用我的钱分别买了些 CHP跟ZXY股
...I split my money and I bought some shares of CHP and ZXY.
你怎么选的？
How come those?
CHP是因为我喜欢过电视剧《Chips》里的艾瑞克艾斯彻达
Well,CHP because I used to have a crush on Erik Estrada.
ZXY是因为听起来像sexy（性感）
And ZXY because I think it sounds "zexy."
那你的…MEG呢？
What happened to MEG?
MEG帮我赚过钱 但是被我甩了
MEG was good for me,but I dumped her.
我的座右铭是在“疲软”以前离开
My motto is,"Get out before they go down."
这不是我的座右铭
That is so not my motto.
狗怎么样了？
How's the dog?
我跟兽医谈过了 纽约州的人真好
Okay. I talked to the vet. People are so nice upstate.
他说那个小家伙不会有问题 明天我可以去接它了
He said the little fella's gonna be okay,and I can get him tomorrow.
好，好极了 谢天谢地
-Good. -Thank God.
可是他必须帮它缝好多针
But he did have to have a bunch of stitches.
而且他还说只有出现蓝月亮时狗才会再长出耳朵来的
And he said that only once in a blue moon does a dog's ear grow back.
所以还有一点点希望
So still hoping.
那你现在要打电话告诉你爸 他的狗没事了吗？
Now are you going to call your dad to let him know that his dog is okay?
我不想在电话上跟我爸相认
I don't want to meet my father over the phone.
我该跟他说什么呢？ “我是被你抛弃的女儿”
What will I say,"Hi,I'm the daughter you abandoned.
“对了，我撞伤了你的狗”
Oh,by the way,I broke your dog."
菲比，我可以帮你打的
Hey,Pheebs,if you want,I'll do it.
听着，拜托千万不要提我的事
Listen,just don't say anything about me,okay?
别…
Don't...
…讲电话太久
... be too long with the phone.
股市收盘以后 她会是个比较好的朋友
She'll be a much better friend once the market closes.
是个女的
It's a woman.
你跟她讲啊
So talk to her.
你好布菲太太
Hello,Mrs. Buffay.
我知道你的狗在哪里
I know where your dog is.
我要你知道 它会被几乎完好无损地归还…
I want you to know he'll be returned to you almost as good as new...
…在24小时之内
...within 24 hours.
再见
Goodbye.
干嘛变声？ 很难解释
-Why the voice? -Hard to say.
你的卡布奇诺来了
Your cappuccino,sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
在这里喝比在咖啡厅好多了 对极了
-This is better than the coffeehouse. -Absolutely.
咖啡粉为什么不化？
How come it's not mixing with the water?
包装上说你必须要不断的搅拌
The package says to keep it moving.
搅拌，喝 别让咖啡停下来
Stir and drink,never let it settle.
这太荒唐了吧
This is ridiculous.
这样吧，等我从外甥女的洗礼回来之后…
After I get back from my niece's christening...
…我陪你们到咖啡馆去喝杯咖啡
...I'll go to the coffeehouse with you and we'll have a cup of coffee.
没问题的，有乔伊在
No problem. Joey's there.
不，我不希望每一次必须有乔伊陪着才能喝杯好咖啡
I don't want to have to have Joey with me every time I want decent coffee.
我也不想再喝这个“k”牌子的卡布奇诺咖啡了
And I don't want to drink cappuccino with a "k."
我认为我们应该回咖啡厅去 勇敢的面对那些人
I say you and I go and stand up to those guys.
好吧，先等等，卡斯特将军（历史上的传奇人物）
All right,hang on a second there,Custer.
真的，罗斯 你以前有没有被扁过？
Ross,have you ever been beaten up before?
有啊，当然有
Yeah,sure.
被莫妮卡以外的人？ 没有
By someone besides Monica?
所以呢？
So what?
就算被扁又怎么样？也许每个男人都得经历过一次这个…
So we get beaten up. Maybe that's something a man has to go through.
就像成人礼之类的
Like a rite of passage or something.
不能只是再失去一次童贞就好吗？
Couldn't we just lose our virginities again?
因为我想我的又长回来了
Because I think actually mine's growing back.
拜托，你到底跟不跟我去？
Are you with me or not?. Come on.
去
I' m with you.
只是…
Just...
让我为进医院提前准备好两件内衣
...Iet me put on a clean pair of underwear for the hospital.
我需要借100 什么？
-I need $100. -What?
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
我需要借一百块 干嘛？
-I need $100. -For what?
我得回到游戏中去 你什么时候退出的？
-To get back in the game. -When did you get out?
我赔光了，全赔了
I lost it all. I lost it.
我接受事实了，你也得这样
I've come to terms with it,you have to,too.
听着，莫妮卡，我很遗憾
Look,Mon,I'm really sorry.
100块钱在哪里？
Where are we on the $100?
我没钱啊
I don't have it.
可是我需要
But I need it!
否则我得接受那个餐馆的工作
Otherwise,I'll have to take that diner job.
你知道的 就是跳舞还有穿戏服
You know,with the dancing and the costumes.
我不想穿连火都烧不着的假胸部
I don't want to have to wear flame-retardant boobs.
没人想，亲爱的
Nobody does,honey.
面条
Noodle!
老天啊，我的狗到底怎么了？
Oh,my God. What the hell happened to my dog?
那是个意外
It was an accident.
而且那个肇事的女人 绝不会蓄意伤害一只狗的
And the woman who did this would never hurt a dog on purpose.
因为她是素食主义者
She's a vegetarian.
这是什么？缝线？
Are these stitches?
对，八针 对狗来说是56针啦
Yeah,eight of them. That's 56 to him.
还有，下雨的时候…
If it's raining,you can't let him look up...
…不要让它抬头太久 因为那玩意儿装不了多少水的
... because that cone will fill up fast.
谢谢你送它的残骸回来
Thanks for bringing back what's left of him.
弗兰克在吗？ 你怎么认识他的？
-ls Frank home? -How do you know Frank?
那是很久以前的事，他在吗？
Just from a long time ago. Is he here?
在，弗兰克？
Yes，Frank？
什么事啊？
What?
我是说，老的弗兰克
I mean Frank Senior.
他去买日用品了
He went out for groceries.
他很快回来吗？
Will he be back soon?
他四年前去的 所以我们猜他随时会回来
He left four years ago. We're expecting him back any minute.
那我要走了
I'm gonna go.
对不起，关于… 关于那只狗
I'm sorry about the dog. Everything.
对不起
I'm sorry.
小姐
Hey,lady!
等一下
Hey,wait up!
你怎么认识我老爸的？ 我不认识他
-How do you know my dad? -Well,I don't really.
基因上认得
Just genetically.
他也算是我老爸吧
He's kind of my dad too.
不得了
Heavy.
他有没有提过我…菲比？
So did he ever talk about me... Phoebe?
没有，不过他一向很沉默
No,but he didn't really talk about anything.
除了高跷
Except stilts.
高跷？ 对啊，他爱高跷
-Stilts? -Yeah,he loved stilts.
有一次我在楼上，正在偷 我妈皮包里面的香烟时…
One time,I was upstairs stealing cigarettes out of my mom's purse...
…突然间我张望了一下…
...and all of a sudden I look over...
…看到我爸的头从窗外经过
...and there's Dad's head,bobbing past the window.
他脸上满是笑意地 向我挥了一挥手…
He just had this big smile on his face and he was waving...
…因为他踩高跷的时候 就是他最高兴的时候了
...because he was happiest when he was on his stilts.
我根本不会踩那玩意儿
I don't know what to do with that.
我也是
Me neither.
所以你是我姐姐？
So are you,like,my big sister?
真不得了，你可以请我喝啤酒
This is huge. You can buy me beer!
我不会这么做
I'm not gonna.
知道怎么样最酷吗？ 如果你有个朋友叫做彼得…
But you know what's cool? If you had a friend named Pete,I could say...
…那我就可说“我认得彼得，他是我弟弟的朋友”
... "I know Pete. He's friends with my brother."
我有个朋友叫马克 那也可以啊
-I got a friend named Mark. -That'll work too.
酷，好
Cool. All right.
或许改天我可以打个电话给你
So maybe,you know,I could give you a call sometime.
我们可以好好聊聊或什么的
We could talk or something.
好啊，那会很好 好
-Yeah,that'd be okay. -All right.
电话簿上有我的电话
I'm in the book.
那…高跷？
So stilts,huh?
你要的话，我可以带你去看 他头撞到排水管的那个地方
If you want,I can show you where he hit his head on the rain gutter.
我们办到了，我们在这儿 我们坚守我们的立场
We did it. We're here. We are standing our ground.
一杯咖啡到底要煮多久？ 快点？快点呀
-How long does coffee take? -Would you come on? Come on!
谢谢
Thank you.
好了，喝完了 我想我们证明了
-There we go. -I think we proved our point.
烫到嘴了没有？ 舌头没感觉了
-You burn your mouth? -Cannot feel my tongue.
流氓，大流氓
Bullies! Big bullies!
看看谁来了？是胆小鬼们
Look who's here. It's the weenies.
我们那天讲得不够清楚 是不是？
Did we not make ourselves clear the other day?
所以我们才来
That's why we're here.
对，我们在坚守立场
Yes,we're standing our ground.
你也看的出来吧
Apparently.
少说废话了
Let's do this already.
你那是什么？武器？
You got a weapon?
一只好表 我不想在槌你的时候弄坏它
A nice watch. I don't want to break it on your ribs.
来吧，来呀
All right,let's do this.
我有问题，若我不在乎我的表 我可以拿下来当武器吗？
Question: If I don't care about my watch,can I use it as a weapon?
什么意思？ 那个很锋利，是金属做的
-What do you mean? -It's sharp,it's metal.
我想这可以用来 发挥很大的杀伤力
I think I can do some serious damage with it.
不，你不能用手表
No,you can't use your watch.
或钥匙
Or your keys.
听我说，这样好了
Here's what we'll do.
把所有的钥匙和手表 都放在这个帽子里面摆在那里
We'll put all keys and watches in the hat over there.
好吗？
All right?
好了，来吧…
All right,come on,man. Let's do it!
趁我还记得，脸可以打吗？
Before I forget,are we hitting faces?
当然可以打，脸为何不能打？
Of course. Why wouldn't you hit faces?
因为我星期一还得上班 我得上台说话
I have to work on Monday. I have a big presentation.
我明天要带人去看房子…
Actually,I gotta show this apartment tomorrow...
…所以不打脸这事 倒是好主意
...and this no-faces thing might not be a bad idea.
脖子以上不准打
Nothing from the neck up.
或腰部以下
Or the waist down.
黛娜在排卵期 真的？你们又在试了？
-Dana's ovulating. -Really? You guys trying again?
好吧，让我先搞清楚 我们只能够打中间的部份吗？
Let me get this straight. We're talking about the middle?
来呀
Come on!
你们要打这边？还是打这边？
You want a piece of this? I'm standing here!
你们看，我们东西被偷了
Those guys are taking our stuff!
天啊，那真是不可思议
God,that was amazing. That was incredible.
你们好厉害 我们？那你们呢？
-You guys kicked butt! -Us? What about you guys?
你们真的 给了那个老贼颜色瞧了
You really gave it to old Mr. Clean back there.
那家伙长得好壮啊 没错，不是吗？
-He was a big guy. -Yeah,he was,wasn't he?
是呀，我不知道，我全错过了
I wouldn't know,having missed everything.
不要太责怪自己了
Don't do that to yourself.
我们不管谁都可能会被那个小女孩的跳绳给绊倒
Any one of us could have tripped over that little girl's jump rope.
对了，两位，那我们…
So listen,guys...
…没事了吧？
...are we okay here?
没事了
We're okay.
那帽子可以还给我了吗？
So can I have my hat back?
看看她
Oh,my God. Look at her.
莫妮卡
Hi,Monica!
顺利吗？
How's it going?
好美的胸
Hey,nice boobs.
各位…看看这个
Guys,guys. Check this out.
YMCA（基督教青年会会歌，经典励志歌曲）
太棒了
Excellent.